

# **Ahmed Imtiaz**

(+92) 3070465698

Date of birth: 12/08/1995

**■ Email address:** writetoahmedimtiaz@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-imtiaz-3578911ab

• Address: Gulshan-e-Ravi, Lahore (Pakistan)

#### **ABOUT ME**

A confident and reliable IT professional with 3+ years of experience of working as a Technical support engineer a nd resolving any support issues that are raised to the service desk. Possessing professional training & certifications from CISCO, Microsoft etc. and have proven track record in network/system support helping clients and colleagues resolve complex technical IT issues. An excellent communicator can relate well with people at all levels and has the flexibility of working well as part of a team and on my own.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Network & System Engineer**

FutureNow Technologies [ 01/2022 - Current ]

City: Lahore

Country: Pakistan

- Proactively ensure the highest levels of systems and infrastructure availability
- Continuous network traffic, critical nodes/endpoints monitoring & ensuring the availability of internet
- Configuration & maintenance of CISCO IP phones, CCTV, IP cameras
- Providing L1/L2 support to all users across the business
- Identifying, diagnosing and rectifying any issues in computer hardware, software, services and applications
- Service desk ticket management (Assign, follow up, resolution & close)
- Use Active Directory and Exchange Management Console for managing users (Create, Unlock & Delete Users, Reset Password)., groups, and computers.
- Scanning of computer systems & servers using BitDefender to ensure virus free IT environment
- Backup of Virtual machines hosted on different ESXI hosts using Veeam backup & replication software.
- Support in day-to-day data center operations
- Liaise with vendors and other IT personnel for problem resolution
- Providing step-by-step technical help, both verbal & written, including procedural documents

#### **Systems Support Engineer**

**Dunya News** [ 04/2021 - 12/2021 ]

City: Lahore
Country: Pakistan

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, printers and scanners
- Continuous monitoring and maintenance of computer systems and networks.
- Providing technical support to all users across the business.
- Responding and resolving the support requests and service tickets in a timely manner
- Identifying, diagnosing and rectifying any issues in computer hardware, software, services and applications
- Setting up AD accounts for new users and assist users with password or login problems

## **IT Support Engineer**

**Lahore Logistics Pvt Ltd** [ 03/2019 - 02/2021 ]

City: Lahore Country: Pakistan

- Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software problems on desktops, laptops and other various computing equipment and devices related to Windows 10, Office and Outlook.
- Diagnose incidents utilizing administration tools or remote-control utilities to troubleshoot PC, operating system or system incidents
- Resolve wide range of software issues either face-to-face or remotely using remote tools such as Anydesk, TeamViewer and MS Teams
- Troubleshooting basic system and network problems and diagnosing, solving hardware or software faults
- Reimage laptops and desktops as needed following company policy
- Installation and support for local and network printers
- Ask customers targeted questions to quickly understand the root of the problem
- Maintain and Update the asset inventory sheet

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

### **BS Software Engineering**

Lahore Leads University, Pakistan [ 2014 - 2018 ]

# F.Sc Pre-Engineering

Govt. college of science, Pakistan [ 2012 - 2014 ]

## **High School**

Pak Angles High School, Pakistan [ 2010 - 2012 ]

### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

IT Support & Troubleshooting / System Support / Network Support / Computer Hardware & Software / Software installation & patch management / Microsoft windows 7/8/10, Android, IOS / Microsoft Office 365 Administration / Networking / Code Versioning: Git, GitHub, GitLab / Routing protocols:RIP, OSPF, EIGRP / Exchange server 2010, 2016 (ADDS, DNS, DHCP) / Virtual Machines (VMWare, Virtual Box ) / Web technologies: HTML5, CSS, BootStrap, JavaScript

# **TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate)**

CISCO

https://www.credly.com/badges/38a496e9-2e60-428a-9af2-12e7a98bd777

### MCSA (Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate) Training

Windows server 2012,2016, Active directory, AD groups & objects, Group policy, AD services such as DNS & DHCP, Hyper-V

#### **Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals**

Microsoft

https://www.credly.com/badges/80648de6-698b-427c-895f-04af94c15b0f